hey guys how's it going i'm back here
with another video of my series where i
teach you guys how to make a credit
application from the beginning
and i know the last video was pretty
long it was like 30 minutes long
but i think this is the last video of my
series so
currently we can read like everything
from the database
and we can also insert everything in our
database
and what we need to do left is maybe
i'm thinking like trying to to make a
way so that whenever you add a movie
to our database you don't need to
refresh the page because currently for
example
if i write here fast
and furious right and
i come here and write very good and i
submit
nothing appears you need to refresh the
page so that it will
fetch the new information from the
database why is this happening
basically we are only wait let me come
to app.js
we're only getting the information
whenever the use effect hook is called
and this only happens once whenever the
page is rendered so we need to fix that
so that whenever we just click here we
don't need to refresh the page
and this is basically one of the best
things that react can do and we're going
to take advantage of that
and also i'm thinking we need to style
this a bit so that we can have like a
nice
card for each movie and in each card
there's going to be
maybe an update button and
a delete button so we can finish the
crud
aspect of our application which like up
it means
basically update and delete and i think
that's it
so the first thing we're going to do is
we're going to make the
application be able to update itself
cons
consistently so let's come here
and you know that we have a movie review
list
this is basically the the list that is
displaying right here with all the names
so whenever we click on submit review i
simply want to add
the the new movie that i'm that i'm
submitting into that list
so i'll just grab set movie list
and i'll come here and i'll erase this
and i'll set the movie list equal to
the current movie list so movie list
and i'm also going to add some dots
before it so
and
want to add the new movie that we're
adding to our database
which is basically an object with the
movie name and the
movie review so um
[Music]
movie name equals to the current movie
name
and review i think it's review
let me look at the object um
let me see when we're displaying
basically
it's a movie name and movie review okay
so movie review
is equal to review so now
whenever we're adding something to the
database we're also
after after making the post request
request we're also
setting the movie list with equal to the
same movie list
but pushing a new element which is the
one we're submitting to our database
and let's try this again so if i add a
movie
for example uh let me think of a movie
um i don't know hobbit
and i give it a review nice
movie and i press submit you can see
that
nothing happens why is it happening let
me let me look at the inspect element
um each child this isn't the problem
let me refresh it and if we refresh it
it works but
why is it not working okay guys i fixed
it basically
i was setting everything on the promise
basically after the post request there
was
a dot then and that wasn't working so
what i would recommend
is just separating both so make the
excuse.post request over here
and then set the movie list so if i come
here and write
the name of a random movie like percy
jackson
and you can see like there's no percy
jackson here
um nice movie
and i press submit now percy jackson
appears here and i don't need to refresh
my page
so basically that's it so what i'm
thinking we need to do now is style this
a bit because you're you're seeing that
this
it's like taking a lot of space it's not
it's not visually
uh pleasing and also like we need to
make it into some cards right
so let's create a card right here so
um over here we're going instead of just
making it making it uh h1 i'm going to
make it a div
and the div will have a class name
of um card
and then inside of here there's going to
be a
an h1 which is basically going to be the
movie
and there's no not like i'm going to
erase this movie name part because
we're gonna try to make it a little bit
prettier so
we're just putting the movie name on the
top and on the bottom we're we're adding
the review
as like a description so let me just
create a paragraph tag and
i'm gonna even erase the movie review
uh label so let's look at this you can
see this is basically how it's gonna
look
it's gonna have the title and on the
bottom the the little review right
but we're gonna make this look better so
app.css
i'm gonna grab here and call the card
and make it um let me think a width
of like 500 pixels
then a height of like 150 pixels
then some borders so border two pixels
solid
and black
let's make it simple and let's add a
border radius because i always think
they look
nice so border radius of like 15 pixels
let's take a look at how it's looking
it's a bit too big
so i'm gonna make this a hundred
and no actually 150 was looking
now 120 and i'm adding a margin to this
so margin
of like 10 pixels okay
it's looking cool um i'm thinking of
maybe
changing the the font just
just so we can like add some style to it
so
font family
and i'm gonna grab something over here
i'm gonna use trebuchet i think this is
the name
i feel like this like i know this font
is really cool so
you can see that everything now looks
pretty good and
let me think what else we can do maybe
now we need to add the two buttons right
the button for delete and the button for
update so let's come to the bottom here
and edit button
delete and
let's add another but let's actually add
a um
how do i say this let's just add an
input right
so input with type
text
and this is going to be the update input
so whatever right here is
basically going to be whatever we want
to change
and we're only going to be able to
change the movie review i'm not going to
make it so that
you can update the title because that
doesn't make like that doesn't make
sense
so and this button is going to be update
okay let's look how it looks it looks
pretty horrible
you know why because we need to grab the
it's not like
it's basically making the input huge
because i set the inputs here
to be huge so that this looks good so
what i'm going to do is i'm going to add
an id for this
so um
id and this id is basically going to be
the
update input and we're going to style it
on our own so if we come here
and write update
input and let me say
width is equal to like 100 pixels maybe
something like that
and height is equal to something small
like 30 pixels
um let's look how it looks um it's still
pretty
not that good i need to increase maybe
the size of the
the card yeah i'm gonna make this 150
again
let's see how it looks now
[Music]
it still doesn't look good maybe
decrease the size of of these things
make this 20 um and add a margin to this
a margin bottom so
margin bottom of like 10 pixels
let's see how it looks it's still the
same so i'm gonna just increase this to
170 and
i think this this should be good yeah so
we have our delete button we have our
update but
our update input and our update button
right so
let's make it so that whenever you click
delete you can delete everything here
so let's come here and create a function
called delete review
const delete review
equal to like the arrow syntax
and let's make an x use dot
delete request and instead of here we're
going to set our url
i'm going to just copy this and
set it right here we're going to set it
equal to a slash api
slash delete because we're going to
create that and
let's send a variable maybe just the
the movie name movie name
and now actually i'm thinking the idea
right
no but we're not setting the id okay so
let's just send the movie name
and that should be good
so let's go to our back end and let's
create a
app.delete api endpoint right so
app.delete
and this is going to be as we mentioned
before slash
api slash delete and there's going to be
a
require a response
and we're going to create a function out
of it so we're going to grab
first the the movie name so const name
equal to rec the body dot movie name
and let's create the
sql syntax for this right
so let's come here and
insert into movie we're gonna change
this
basically this is going to be delete
from the name of the database
the name of the table so movie reviews
and where
and this is the case right so where
movie name equal to whatever we're
setting right so
let's grab movie name and i'm going to
explain this better
movie name equal to question mark so
basically what we're saying here is
delete from the table where the movie
name
is equal to the movie name that we set
over here so
we're deleting whatever movie has this
name and
if we come here the reason why we're
putting a question
mark as i said in the last video is so
that we can sanitize our input so
basically
we can just set the variable here
instead of directly
inside of the the string and this is
important for
for various different reasons so if i
come here and put
database.query and i add
the sql oh i'm going to change this name
so ask
ql delete and i add this variable here
and then on the side i add the name and
as you can see like
since this is only taking one variable i
don't need to create a
an array like i created last time
because this time i was setting two
variables two question marks and this
one i'm only setting once
and that also comes into place when i'm
when i'm sending
the data through the access request as
you can see on the
actual stop post where we inserted data
into the database
we're sending two pieces of information
the movie name and the movie review
that's why we created an object but in
this case we're only setting
uh one object one one variable which is
the movie name so we don't really need
to create an object out of it
so now we have this function right here
right so we have the delete review
and we created the app.delete
route on the back end we just need to
then set a a function out of this so
error results and
let's grab this information and i'm also
going to do this
so inside of here if we have any error
let's console.log
[Music]
the error and let's
only do this if there is any error so
um if error then do this
and let's see what happens right so we
have the endpoint
and we come here and we do this we just
need to set the delete review
whenever we click the button so let's
come to the delete button
and press on click equal to
delete review right so for example if
i'm trying to delete
the this review right here
i can just come here and press delete
and when i refresh the page
nothing happens let's see what error
appeared so i get what's happening
basically we we can't just set an object
like this
we're going to try to send the object
through the parameters of
the url itself right so basically
instead of just calling it slash api
slash delete
we're going to call slash api slash a
variable and we're going to pass the
variable directly on the route and this
variable is going to be the movie name
so i'm going to remove this and
i'm going to even change this quotes to
become
this this type of quote because then we
can pass variables inside of this
and inside of here we're going to set
the movie name
but i just realized something as well i
was setting the movie name
as whatever to object we're trying to
delete
but this is incorrect because the movie
name represents the variable
that is currently being written on the
the input right so
basically we want to delete the specific
uh movie that we're trying to
that we're clicking the button so for
that we need to pass a variable
inside of the delete function so on the
on click event i'm going to
create this this syntax so that we can
pass a variable to our function
and over here on the delete review i'm
going to pass the
value the movie name so that for every
delete review
we have a different movie that we're
passing so
if i come here and i create um
a name over here like for example movie
and instead of movie name i said here
movie then now we're sending the correct
information
to our backend and if we come back to
our to our back and i'm going to change
some stuff
on instead of slash api slash delete
we're going to
make slash api slash delete and we're
going to add the following syntax which
is
how you create a way so that you can
pass parameters to your
your route we're going to add the colon
and then the name of your of whatever
variable we're passing so we're passing
a movie name
and over here instead of wreck the body
we're grabbing
rack.params and now this should be
completely correct
if i come back here and i refresh my
browser and i try to delete
this right here and i click delete you
can see that now it's completely deleted
from our database it's deleted from our
from our front end it's all correct
right so now we have
the following project so it's working we
have a delete functionality
we just need to do one more thing which
is create the update functionality
so we're coming back to our backend and
let's create another route called
um another api endpoint sorry
called app.put and
instead of this is going to be the
update slash update
and we're grabbing we're doing it based
on the movie review
right so we're grabbing should we
actually do it based on no we're doing
based on
movie name but we're trying to update
the movie review so
let's change this to an sql update
and for those who don't know the the
syntax or the command to update
stuff under mysql database or any other
sql type language
basically you just need to write update
set
wait update set
basically let's think the name of the
the table right so movie reviews
and the name of the column so we're
trying to update
movie review
is the name of the column equal to
question mark and the question mark is
something we're going to is the variable
that we're going to pass right here
so oh i also need to write a where right
so where
um movie name equals to this so
basically
we're saying update the the table movie
reviews and set the
the column movie review equal to some
variable
where the movie name is equal to
something so we're specifying
which column we want to change based on
the movie name
and for that reason we need to grab two
things we need to grab the movie name
and the movie
and the movie review right so movie
review
and we're not gonna use params we're
gonna use buddy
so wreck the body and correct the body
the movie review it's going to be really
similar to the insert statement
and over here we're not we're not
passing only one variable so we need to
pass an array
and we need to put it in order right so
the first variable that we're asking is
the movie review
so we're going to pass the review
and the second one is the name okay
and we're going to change this to sql
update and this should be
working so basically i forgot to mention
that
this is this is the the four different
ways you can treat an http request
you can get information which is the the
read part of the crud you can post
information which is the
the insert part or the create part
then whenever you want to delete there's
the delete and whenever you want to
update there's the put
so this is how you you always work with
the different
http requests so let's go to our front
end
and let's create a function called
um update review
update review
and let's grab here and
let's try to make let's try to pass a
variable we're passing the movie name
so yeah let's let's still use movie and
instead of this
let's change it to xs.put and let's
remove this let's make it a simple
url without any params and
this is going to be api update right
and let's pass another variable just
like we did on the app.post
because we can do this for the update
and
let's create a state right we need to
create a state for the variable that
we're currently
like the input that we're currently
currently trying to change so
like let's come here and write const
um new
review and set
new review and let's
create a use state and set it equal to
an empty
string right so um whenever we
work whenever on the whenever we change
the input
we want to set the
[Applause]
let me right here so when i set the
set the new review equal to
the event which we didn't create yet so
e dot target
dot value right this is really simple
this is what we did on the other
inputs in our application and now we're
setting the new review equal to this
we also want to um whenever we finish
this we want to clear
so set our new review variable equal to
an empty string so that we can use it
again if we're trying to update
different movie reviews right so
set new review
equal to an empty stream because
whenever we finish sending this
information
we're using the same variable for every
single movie review
so we want to set it equal to we want to
clear it you know
so this should be right and the movie
we're passing the movie and the review
we're passing the new
review so let's also
create an unclick event for this just
like we did for the delete button
because we're going to pass a variable
here and
let me write update review and we're
going to pass the
move the value the movie name
right just like the the delete button so
i have a feeling that this should be
working but as i mentioned
something there there's always something
wrong so
let's try this i'm going to refresh
everything and i want to change the
inception
review from good movie to awesome movie
and let me click update let's refresh
the screen
and it didn't work let's look at what
happened so
and we're back it didn't take long uh
i i kind of already knew when i looked
at my code again
i already figured it out and as you can
see we changed everything
basically i wrote the sql statement
wrong it's not update set
the name of the table and the columns
it's update the name of the table
set the columns where movie name is
equal to this
it's really simple i don't know why i
did that but that's okay
so you can see that if i come here and
first of all i'm going to delete
all the smurfs so okay and if i want to
change
a harry potter to the best
movie franchise
in his story of
cinema and i click update and i refresh
the page you can see that
it correctly updated everything and it
will keep it that way because we're
updating it in our database
and i don't know if this video is too
long but we created our whole credit
application
so yeah i hope you guys enjoyed this
video i hope you guys like this series
um i'm still thinking of making some
series where i actually make it look
good
because i know this this looks like
but i'm trying to
just focus on functionality but i'm also
really interested in working on the
front end
with doing some css so i'm definitely
thinking of doing some series where i
teach you guys how to work
with that in a better and more more like
visually
appealing way you know if you know what
i mean so i hope you guys enjoyed this
series
it was really nice doing this for you
guys and if you have any any
questions any doubts please leave a
comment down below if you enjoyed this
series
please like this video and i see you
guys next time
[Music]