hey guys how's it going i'm back here
with another video of my series where i
teach you guys how to make a credit
application from the beginning
and i know the last video was pretty
long it was like 30 minutes long
but i think this is the last video of my
series so
currently we can read like everything
from the database
and we can also insert everything in our
database
and what we need to do left is maybe
i'm thinking like trying to to make a
way so that whenever you add a movie
to our database you don't need to
refresh the page because currently for
example
if i write here fast
and furious right and
i come here and write very good and i
submit
nothing appears you need to refresh the
page so that it will
fetch the new information from the
database why is this happening
basically we are only wait let me come
to app.js
we're only getting the information
whenever the use effect hook is called
and this only happens once whenever the
page is rendered so we need to fix that
so that whenever we just click here we
don't need to refresh the page
and this is basically one of the best
things that react can do and we're going
to take advantage of that
and also i'm thinking we need to style
this a bit so that we can have like a
nice
card for each movie and in each card
there's going to be
maybe an update button and
a delete button so we can finish the
crud
aspect of our application which like up
it means
basically update and delete and i think
that's it
so the first thing we're going to do is
we're going to make the
application be able to update itself
cons
and you know that we have a movie review
list
this is basically the the list that is
displaying right here with all the names
so whenever we click on submit review i
simply want to add
the the new movie that i'm that i'm
submitting into that list
so i'll just grab set movie list
and i'll come here and i'll erase this
and i'll set the movie list equal to
the current movie list so movie list
and i'm also going to add some dots